Elnaz Doostdar Portfolio

San Mateo, CA 94403 <u>LinkedIn</u> 949.607.6136 elnazd@gmail.com

Senior UX Designer

Lead design efforts of delivering innovative design solutions using an expert usability approach to create meaningful journeys for complex enterprise software products used by millions of highly technical engineers. Develop strong relationships with UX researchers, developers, product managers, stakeholders, and users by tailoring a flexible style to meet success.

Technical Skills

User Research Survey / Interview, Empathy Map, Competitive Analysis, Literature Review, User Flow,

Affinity Diagram, Persona, Journey Map, Usability Testing

Design Hand Sketch, Wireframe, Hifi Mockup, Prototype, Information Architecture, Design

System, Responsive Web, iOS & Android

Development HTML5, CSS3, jQuery / JavaScript, Bootstrap, React

Tools Figma, Miro, Sketch, Adobe Suite (XD / Photoshop / Illustrator), Balsamiq, InVision,

Frontify, Zeplin, Visual Web Optimizer, Keynote

Professional Experience

EQUINIX, Sunnyvale, CA

Jun 2020 - Present

Senior UX Designer

- Design an interactive centralized network topology feature empowering network architects to explore, monitor, and troubleshoot their entire network and build efficient network design solutions.
- Redesign Equinix interconnection portal information architecture to help customers map features based on their roles in networking and reflect relationships based on users' mindsets to improve discoverability.
- Create an automated online self-service ordering experience for reserving servers that reduces expenses for both customers and the business.
- Contribute to the Equinix design system by leading workshops to gather and synthesize ideas to scale and improve components.

QUEST SOFTWARE, Aliso Viejo, CA Senior UX / UI Designer

Jan 2016 - Feb 2020

Jan 2018 - Feb 2020

- Preserved 15% of PMs' time on executing projects from planning to closure by designing project planning and reporting features for an internal enterprise product from conception to implementation, improving workflow for several departments.
- Initiated building a scalable responsive/accessible design library and defined maintenance process slashed design deliverables time 50% and enhanced design consistency across platforms and contributed to 2 major acquisitions rebranding process.

- Launched stunning responsive campaigns, landing, and product information web pages worked seamlessly across 6 different languages on the company marketing website.
- Achieved 10% in deflection by redefining and automating user-flow challenges to contact support.

UX / UI Designer Jan 2016 - Jan 2018

- Evaluated and redesigned Quest e-commerce to create visually stimulating UI and delightful user experience; collaborated with users, stakeholders, and developers. Yielded reduction in customer support costs by 20%.
- Led qualitative and quantitative research efforts such as A/B testing using visual web optimizer, validating
 designs and training team members improving conversion rate.
- Pioneered resolving problems by introducing new tools, facilitating hand-off procedures to developers, accelerating work efficiency.

DELL, Aliso Viejo, CA Mar 2014 - Jan 2016

UI Developer

- Launched pixel-perfect responsive web pages using Bootstrap framework amplified traffic and reduced bounce rate on tablet and mobile.
- Delivered a video gallery site using complex Ajax technology, enabling Dell to integrate overall video strategy across platforms improving accessibility.

QUICKSTART INTELLIGENCE, Irvine, CA

May 2013 - Mar 2014

UI Developer

- Developed interactive responsive components in collaboration with remote engineers boosting mobile traffic by 50%.
- Analyzed data and conducted qualitative usability tests with users, improving course registration rates by 0.2%

Side Projects FREELANCE

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

Product Designer

- Designed a COVID-19 protection concept <u>mobile app</u> to help contain the Coronavirus through heatmaps, test symptoms, quarantine instructions, and assigning available healthcare facilities accordingly.
- Designed a healthcare mobile app to support virtual care adopted by <u>Zocdoc</u> application.

Education

- Master of Information Technology, Web Development, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia
- Bachelor of Computer Science, Hardware Engineering, Azad University, Tehran, Iran
- Certificate of User Experience and Customer-Centered Design, California State University Fullerton, CA